[Episode 11]
Why are you...
Halt!
Identify yourselves.
Unhand her.
I said unhand her.
My Lord.
Are you deaf?
Unhand her now!
Get them!
Back away or I'll cut her.
- My Lord.
- Stop this or we'll stop you.
Now!
- Are you alright?
- My Lord.
What are you doing here
at this time of night?
Your orders, Sir?
They look like common criminals.
Hand them over to the local police.
Sir.
The King's not in the palace?
No. He was looking for you
at the Police Bureau.
What?
Well? What were you doing here?
Thank you, My Lord.
You saved my life.
What have I told you?
Go out early.
If I hadn't come by,
who knows what might have happened.
I'm sorry, My Lord,
but this was especially important.
Especially?
I was looking for you, actually.
For me?
For me? Why?
I had to tell you something.
I went to the administrative offices.
You what?
But the guard said
you'd never heard of me.
Why'd you say that, though?
I'm not sure...
Wait! The guard went to Officer Kang,
of course. That's it.
Huh?
There are two inspectors in our office.
Kang's the other one.
- Ah, so that's it?
- Of course. I'd never say that.
Ah, I see. I thought maybe
you'd forgotten me.
So what was so important that
you had to come find me?
Well, it's this way...
What?
The King saved her?
Yes, Sir. The royal guard turned
them over to the local police.
Luckily they're being tried as
common criminals. We're safe on that score.
But what went wrong? The King saving
a servant? Why would he do that?
Sire.
I spoke with the girl on the way here.
Do we really have information
that clears Lady Jang?
Yes, Sire.
Where's the body?
I need to see it.
Sire.
- Show His Highness.
- Sir.
- Now with some pinellia on your hands.
But... How could...
Contact with pinellia would have
discolored the doctor's hands.
That's what happened, Sire.
This proves the pharmacist
didn't send pinellia to Lady Jang.
And Dongyi discovered this?
Yes, Sire.
Someone murdered the doctor
over an old grudge.
We made the arrest and failed
to examine the corpses carefully.
She saw what hundreds officers missed.
Is everything ready for the inquisitors?
Yes.
They'll be here soon. You understand
we can't let this tarnish our reputation?
Yes, My Lady.
You've done well. You can all expect
a reward for such a satisfactory conclusion.
With special thanks to Lady Yu.
Not at all.
When this is over we'll pay
a visit to the Queen Mother.
Ma'am?
She'd like to thank us for our work
with the inspectorate.
Just as you say. I'll be waiting.
That's wonderful.
An audience with the Queen!
You're bound to be the next
Lady Inspector General.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
It's not over yet.
Yes, ma'am.
These are our prescription records.
- May I have this?
- Of course.
I picked up the prescription myself.
I'm certain there was no pinellia, My Lady.
- Sanghi!
- What did you learn?
The girl was right.
None of the usual vendors
supplied pinellia to that pharmacy.
None?
Well, Your Highness?
Will you accept this small token?
If so, you can rest easy.
We can finally put this behind us.
I'll be much relieved.
Impudent little... Do you think
your influence will last forever?
Lady Do to see you.
- You asked for me, Your Highness?
- Yes.
Prepare my things for a short visit.
Where to, Your Highness?
Lady Jang is being transferred
to the inquisitors.
It's only fitting I see her off.
What's that?
Reopen the case?
None of the vendors supplied this
dead pharmacist with the pinellia.
Pardon?
Lady Jung was right.
The vendors stopped supplying it
after someone died from pinellia.
The girl from the royal
musiciangs office was right.
- We should give the inquisitors the facts.
- Facts?
What facts are those?
- Your Ladyship.
Just because there's no record
doesn't mean he never used it.
He may have bought
the pinellia in secret.
- But...
- Enough of your buts!
The pinellia was in Lady Jang's chambers.
What other proof do we need?
My Lady... My Lady...
It's just awful! Come quick!
Wait... Isn't that the palace guard?
Where are the inquisitors?
They didn't come to transfer Lady Jang.
They came to protect her.
- Huh?
- What?
She was scheduled to be transferred
at 8 a.m., isn't that right?
So I understand.
Find out what happened.
- Of course.
- Your Highness...
Oh, it's unheard of!
What's unheard of?
The King has rescinded Lady Jang's
transfer to the inquisitors.
What's that? On what grounds?
Innocent? It's impossible.
- The facts were...
- Facts?
Here are your facts!
Straight from the Police Bureau.
It proves she's innocent.
The King confirmed the facts himself.
Who do you think uncovered the facts?
A girl from the Office of Royal Musicians.
Pardon?
Do you see now?
What you couldn't see
in your haste was perfectly clear
to a simple servant girl.
Now what? Who will bear
the brunt of this disgrace?
Wait here. We'll have
a few questions for you.
Yes, Sir.
That's the one.
That wisp of a girl proved
Lady Jang is innocent?
So I'm told.
Dongyi cleared my name?
She did indeed.
You've been unjustly accused.
The King commands that Lady Jang
be given full royal escort to her home.
- My Lady.
This must have been difficult for you.
What does that matter?
We're beside ourselves knowing
you were so unjustly accused.
We beg your forgiveness.
I doubt we can ever be free
of this terrible disgrace.
Well? Beg the lady for forgiveness.
Forgive us.
We were entirely in the wrong.
We throw ourselves at your mercy.
Actually, you shouldn't
be apologizing to me.
Ask forgiveness of the servant girl
that saw clearer than you.
She learned the truth despite
all of you. Isn't that right?
Well, Lady Yu? When you're
no better than a servant girl.
It makes me fear for the future
of the Inspector General.
Well? Make way for the lady.
Bring me Dongyi.
She's the first one I want to see.
As you say.
Ma'am, please try to relax.
A musician? I'm disgraced
because of a servant?
The world's turned upside down, I swear.
When a musician can do this to us?
Our reputationgs shot.
That's my point. Everybody's heard
about it. We'll be a joke.
She's nothing. Even napping fishermen
catch something if the net's big enough.
What about you? Did you even
bother tossing out a net?
Ma'am.
Little twits. You think you have
any right to be angry?
If you don't like it,
apply yourselves harder next time.
Well? Are you still here?
I don't understand.
How did a servant think of it?
Good point.
I'm surprised too.
You two discovered facts.
You should mention...
It would only sound like excuses.
Making excuses is worse than making
a mistake in the first place.
We were clearly mistaken.
None of us was as clever as
this servant girl.
- Lady Jo reporting.
- Enter.
Dongyi is with me.
Send her in.
Enter.
Welcome.
My Lady.
- Have a seat.
- Thank you.
I'm at a loss. No words can express
my gratitude.
Not at all. It's nothing compared to the
grace and kindness you've shown me.
Nothing, you say?
I'm returned safely to my home
and you call it nothing?
My Lady...
I knew you're a gifted girl
but I confess I'm surprised.
What made you think of it?
It... It was faith.
Pardon?
Faith that you couldn't
possibly have done it.
Faith that there had to be proof,
that the body would reveal the truth.
What I did was nothing.
I'm nothing. I don't know where I'd be
if you hadn't shown me such kindness.
You're wrong.
You're a clever girl,
but today you're wrong.
My Lady?
You're nothing? No.
To me... You're very precious indeed.
My Lady.
Here we go again.
Lady Jang unjustly imprisoned and
her accuser has disappeared.
Worse, it's less than a month since
this happened the last time.
You see this is what's wrong with
our current system, don't you?
What bothers me isn't Lady Jang,
it's our entire government.
This is all due to your political infighting,
your power plays and endless slander.
We're destroying ourselves from
the inside and don't even know it.
Forgive us, Sire.
It's my fault for thinking you could
control yourselves.
Now you will listen to your King.
This will not be forgiven again.
I will find the one behind this.
And whoever it is, I will show no mercy.
Is that understood?
Forgive us, Sire.
Actually, I'm the most to blame.
Didn't I say it was politics
to overlook their crimes?
It bothered you when I asked you
to look the other way, didn't it?
Well... That is...
It's not your way to be a sycophant.
Forgive me, Sire.
But the days of looking
the other way are over.
I want you to help me
find the one behind this.
It won't be easy.
And it won't be quick.
And the instigator may be
too highly placed.
But I know you'll never stop,
whoever it is.
Remember what I've said.
Be thorough.
I will give it my full attention, Sire.
What's taking Dongyi so long?
Lady Jang's probably giving her
some fancy reward...
Better yet...
A banquet. Chances are
it's another royal banquet.
Huh? Another one?
I thought she'd lost it when she said
she had to yak with a corpse.
But look at her now!
And me, if I'd only known...
I would've trotted after her and joined
in the conversation.
Dongyi!
What's going on?
What did you get?
Show us!
What are you doing?
Hands off.
Gold? Silk? Some cash maybe?
No, it's just...
- Ugh.
- Stinky...
What the? Boots?
Why are these things in here?
Lord Jang told me to clean
and mend them.
So you didn't get no reward or nothing?
Reward?
Yeah reward. She really didn't
give you nothing?
Right. Nothing.
Sir...
Why are you all?
Ah, so you thought this was a reward?
Well Yeah. Big doings earn big rewards
like a banquet maybe?
Come on, I didn't do it for a reward.
Hush, hush! Maybe you didn't...
but what about the King?
You saved his Lady Jang yet again.
All the same...
We're probably acting too soon.
Last time the banquet was the following day,
so we should wait.
Right. It takes a day
to prepare the feast, at least.
How will you feel
when they don't make anything?
That's not going to happen.
Think we'll get the steamed fish?
You like that?
Me, I like the grilled beef.
I'll starve myself tonight.
Good thinking.
We won't eat nothing.
But...
Your fish, Sir...
Come on, quick, give it here...
Your beef, Sir...
What's got into them, I swear...
You sent the medicines to Lady Jang?
I did, but may I ask why?
When I think about her conduct...
Let's have no more of that.
She went through enough over my tonic.
Your Majesty.
You gave her my compliments?
I didn't see her in person.
The King was with her.
- Was he?
- He was.
I understand a servant girl from
the musicians saved the lady.
So I understand as well.
Even Lady Jang's servants are remarkable.
I find myself a little jealous of her.
Your Majesty.
Were you terribly upset with me?
I already told you.
Just seeing you makes it all better.
Thank you for saying so.
We owe a lot to this Dongyi of yours.
When I think a simple servant girl...
Well, it's surprising to say the least.
Yes, Sire. Very much so.
I think her talents are wasted running
errands for the royal musicians.
Sire, if I may beg a favor?
A favor? For her?
Yes, Sire.
Go easy.
No need to strain anything.
I have to catch up on all the stuff
I didn't do yesterday.
Sorry.
All the same you've got a bad lot.
I mean, you do this great thing, right?
And you're still a servant
slaving all day.
Got that right. Someone with your
talent born in a low caste.
If you'd been born a boy, even one level up,
things would be different.
Oh, enough of that.
We all get lucky sometimes.
I'll put this music away.
What good is a caste system when someone
like her is stuck at the bottom?
Moron... what are you thinking?
You really intend to use her?
Yes, if the King permits.
It's an opportunity for her. And for me.
Dongyi is clever enough, I admit...
- But the outcry in the palace...
- That's not for you to say.
Of course.
Oh, do you have news of my Brother?
Yes, he sailed from Qing.
He'll arrive in Doseong soon.
I'd like him to meet Dongyi.
He's good at reading people.
I'd like to see what he makes of her.
Are you heading straight home?
No, I have a few things
to take care of first.
Sir?
I'm going to let this city
know I've returned.
Where is it?
8 a.m., he says.
So where is he?
What if they start the feast without me?
- Excuse me.
- You want a room, right?
- Exactly, I was...
- Good, great, Come on!
Right.
This is it. Nice, huh?
Roomy for the price too.
You know I'm a Royal Musician,
don't you?
So I understood.
I'm the artistic type so I really hate dirt.
Like this for example.
Dirt is so dirty.
I'll keep the room clean.
See that you do.
I'm more of a fighter than a talker,
so just you do what you're told!
- Sound good?
- Of course.
Make yourself at home.
I've got to go do some stuff.
Yes, Sir.
Another court musician of all things,
just like Dongju.
Argh, I'm late!
You... You have to save me...
Me?
Please.
You see someone go in there?
- Someone?
- In there. I saw him.
What the? That's my house.
Move it, turkey.
I got your turkey right here...
Turkey this!
You two in it together, huh?
Save me! Somebody!
Unhand him.
Whatever this is, it's his house.
So hands off.
Another turkey!
Rotten little!
You should get while the getting's good.
Let's git.
No... Don't...
Are you hurt, Sir?
Yeah, great, nothing wrong here.
Whoa, that was really something.
You got a name?
This the man they were chasing?
It is.
What are you up to exactly?
Not much.
Just me and his wife is all.
Huh? Come again?
So his wife wants a little on the side,
nothing for him to worry about.
Don't you think?
I swear, he has no clue what I'm saying...
What? Jang Hijae is back?
And in trouble the second he gets here?
Yes. He had to buy his way
out of a fix yet again.
How did Lady Jang end up
with such a pathetic Brother?
It's nothing to concern yourself with, Sir.
It works out better for us this way.
Wouldn't it be worse if he tried to use
Lady Jang's position to get ahead?
Even so, we should find him a position
where he can't do any harm.
Yes, Sir.
Yeah, he's back today, Father.
Yes!
Uh-oh, now that the womanizer's back
it'll be hard on poor Madam Yun.
Yep. That's a fact.
Now Jang Hijae is here,
I have a friend in Doseong, Father.
Yep, yep, let's have him for a drinks.
- I'll arrange it.
- Yep, yep.
First day back and already
making trouble? When will it end?
True, true.
It makes me sick too.
Huh? Are you making excuses?
- Not at all.
- Hush. I can't stand to look at you.
And a girl from the palace in the house.
It's mortifying.
A girl?
Yes. The servant that saved
your Sister from the inquisitors.
In our house, you say?
Do you have any idea what
your Sister's been through?
Will she ever be able to rely on you?
Where's the girl?
So you're her.
May I ask your name, Sir?
Not a total loss, I'd say.
- Sir, why are you?
- Why? Don't you like it?
Relax. Definitely not my type.
Huh?
Sir, Madam has asked to see her.
Off with you.
She's asking for you.
Yes, Sir.
Hijae.
Your Ladyship.
When did you get here?
Today. I rushed here
the second we landed.
I've been waiting for you to come back.
Yes, me too.
Waiting and yearning.
Is that why you misbehaved
the second you landed?
You heard, huh?
Yes, you would have.
I need people to think of me
as a womanizer and a loafer.
They won't watch me as closely.
- Hijae...
- The time isn't right.
This idleness is killing me
but it's not time yet.
No, it's time, Hijae.
Do you recall my oath
when I first came to the palace?
I swore I'd gain the highest position
I could, remember?
Our days of watching are over.
Now we walk the path we've waited
for so long.
There can be no hesitation
once this starts.
I agree.
I've been helped by a young girl.
She's clever and trustworthy.
She'll be the stone that makes waves
in the calm of the inner court.
The servant from the Office
of Royal Musicians?
You've heard about her?
Heard and seen, I dare say.
- You met her?
- Yes.
And? I value your impressions
above all others.
What is it? Didn't you like her?
Hijae.
I can see what you like about her,
really I can.
But I don't think I'd keep her too close.
What?
I'm looking for belts
for the court musicians.
- Take your time.
- Thank you.
- My Lord.
- If it isn't Pungsan?
- This is such a coincidence.
- Isn't it just?
Small world.
You're running errands?
I am. No accidents today.
Really? You can do that?
You think all I do is make trouble?
What brings you here?
Me? I came to see how regular folks live.
You mean they're all going hungry
in hopes of a big feast?
Yes, I feel awful about it.
The King isn't likely to do it again.
Exactly right. When I spoke with
the King it hadn't even occurred to him.
- Really.
Nothing extra this time.
Does that make you sad?
No. Not even a little bit.
I bet it does.
No, I mean it.
But they're all waiting...
Then allow me.
Sir?
I'll reward you in the King's stead.
Come on. From me or the King,
it's the same in the end.
- Come on.
- Sir.
- I can't...
- Come on.
Is that Dongyi?
Yes, but who's the guy?
- Anything?
- Anything andeverything!
Wait... He couldn't be...
Come with me. We'll pick it together.
He is!
No, it's fine, really.
- Let's see something for the girl.
- Yes, Sir.
Sir...
What do we have here...
This looks good. This too.
We'll take them all.
What are you?
They're so expensive...
Don't worry.
I came into some cash today.
About this silk...
I don't need all of this.
But I want to get it for you.
Dongyi! Dongyi!
Sir? Sir!
You know them?
Yes, they're court musicians.
Forgive them. It appears my men
mistook you for someone else.
- Sir, this is...
- We know.
You're the inspector from the
administrative office.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Bang Yeongdal...
And I'm Head Musician Hwang Jusik.
Nice to meet you both. I understand
your eyes are popping out from hunger.
They popped already,
but I put them back in.
I helped pop.
Want to see?
Sirs!
Why shouldn't I keep her too close?
Hijae?
When have I ever had a reason
for my impressions?
But she's too much like you to suit me.
What?
You're of humble birth but talented
far beyond her station.
That's how you've achieved
what you have.
One of you is enough.
Why give wings for another
like you to fly as high?
Sir, let me buy you a drink.
Yeah, thanks to you we got a royal feast.
Don't you need to get back to your office?
Not today. I've got plenty of time.
You go on. I need a word with my men.
- Thank you.
- Hurry up now!
Sire, this isn't safe.
Allow us to escort you back.
No, it's fine. Keep your distance.
- Sire...
- Hey... Come on!
Fine, go on, go on.
How tall is that guy anyway?
- Sir, another drink.
- No, no, I've had enough.
What? What kind of man is
drunk after three glasses?
Down the hatch. Or else!
He has a particularly weak constitution.
I'll have his.
Huh? No.
- I'll do it.
- Sir.
You alright?
Of course. Why wouldn't I be?
Now your turn. A royal toast.
- Royal?
- Better watch what you say.
Only the King can make a royal toast.
Not the first time. Once he said,
"That's a command" instead of
"That's an order."
You know, you do look like the King.
You think so?
I've seen him across the room at
royal banquets. What do you say, Yeongdal?
I say you're drunk. The King is so
handsome and this guy...
Ahem. Not that you're not handsome.
It's alright. I can handle that the King's
better looking than me.
Is he really that handsome?
I've never seen him.
How can I say either way?
Huh?
Listen, someone told me
the King shines from within.
A strong nose, skin like pearls,
just like the inspector. Exactly.
Ah, is that so?
You're a girl so you like
the good-looking ones, yeah?
Not me. I like them tan
with broad shoulders.
Huh?
Oopsies, your glass is empty.
I'm pouring!
Pour lots.
Less drinking, more eating, there we go...
That's really good!
You think so?
The consistency is just how I like it.
What's it called?
Pig skin.
Right, pig... What skin?
Pig. You know, oink-oink?
Pig skin? I've got a pig's skin
in my mouth?
You're more open-minded
than you look.
Open? Well, I guess I am.
My open-minded Lord,
have another!
This has been really fun.
Are you alright? This is the first time
you've done this, I think.
Yes, the first. I've had lots of firsts
since we met.
I'm glad. I worried you might think
it was all beneath you.
No, this is something I've wanted
for a long time.
You wanted?
Yes. To walk the streets,
just like regular folk.
And you? Is there something
you've always wanted?
Me?
I got to stop being me for a while.
What would you do
if you could stop being you?
What could a servant girl dare
to wish for?
And if I dared,
I could never have it.
Never? Perhaps you'd wish
to stop being a servant?
Sir?
It's clear you're a bright and talented girl.
It's only natural to wish for more.
Denying it would be a lie.
If I weren't born a servant...
If I were a man...
Who wouldn't think about that?
But wishing won't change anything.
Maybe in the next life I'll be born
with opportunities...
That would be my wish.
You may not have to wait.
Pardon?
Things may soon change for you
the same way you changed things
for me tonight.
I hope to make better use of her, Sire.
How so?
It's a shame to waste her talents
simply because of her station.
May I ask your help to allow her gifts
to be put to good use?
- We'll call on the Queen.
- Sire.
Dongyi!
Hurry, you're in such a big...
Huh?
How can... How?
What will we...
Dongyi...
Dongyi, quick, they've asked for you.
Please have the order rescinded.
It's unheard of.
Palace Affairs has already issued
the decree.
My Lady...
Dongyi, servant in the Office of Royal
Musicians, hear the official decree.
The decree.
Dongyi, servant in the Office of
Royal Musicians, listen and obey.
On this, the 11th day of March, 1686,
Dongyi is ordered to enter the
Inner Court as a court lady.
Your new duties will include working
in the Office of the Inspector General.
You are commanded to honor
your new office and this nation.
Me? A court lady?
Me?